# SRI HARSHA CHILAKAPATI

Bengaluru, India · +91 9494607964

 $sriharshachilakapati@gmail.com \cdot goharsha.com \cdot github.com/sriharshachilakapati$ 

A self-enthusiast developer who is interested in developing applications for platforms of interest such as Android, Web, Desktop and also iOS. Had experience in building real-time applications optimized for performance. I'm always interested in exploring tech.

## **EXPERIENCE**

10<sup>TH</sup> FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II

APNATIME TECH

- Revamped the entire Job Feed, Job Search and Job Collection screens in app with re-architecture and developed in-house Figma perfect Shadow renderer for job cards as part of Jobs 2.0 story.
- Worked on the Pan India job liquidity story, which by allowing users to apply in other cities, increased the screened leads by 4%.
- Profiled app code and refactored to reduce overdraw from 11x to 3x and brought frametimes down to 14ms per frame.
- Made everything in Feed, Search, Collection and Details screens backend driven, detailing down to fonts, gradients and custom shadow specs.

**1<sup>ST</sup> OCTOBER 2019 – 10<sup>TH</sup> FEBRUARY 2022** 

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER**

**JUSPAY** 

- Optimized Gradle build pipeline to make builds faster by 65% from 2 minutes to 13 seconds.
- Created new SDK architecture for Hyper SDK 2.0, a flagship product of Juspay.
- Created a Chrome DevTools plugin which allows debugging of native Android Views.
- Wrote 2 Gradle plugins to generate code and assets for merchants resulting in reduction of merchant specific flavours in the HyperSDK code base.

**1<sup>ST</sup> JUNE 2018 – 30<sup>TH</sup> SEPTEMBER 2019** 

#### ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

JUSPAY

- Part of the payment page team and worked on payment pages for Ola Money, Cred and Big Basket.
- Took ownership of Payment Pages for Foodpanda and Bounce (Android & iOS).
- Created the VIES merchant demo app (Android) at Juspay.

4<sup>TH</sup> DECEMBER 2017 – 31<sup>ST</sup> MAY 2018

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERN**JUSPAY

- Implemented 2 screens (Settings & User Profile) in BHIM UPI App.
- Worked on Android module of Presto UI called Mystique, which is a React Native like framework for Juspay.

## **PROJECTS**

- <u>FakeCaller (A POC app to demonstrate working of TrueCaller)</u>
- SilenceEngine (Game Engine for Desktop, HTML5 and Android)
- WebGL4J (WebGL bindings for Java language using GWT)
- GWT-AL (An OpenAL implementation on top of Web Audio API)
- YT Private Subscriptions (iOS App that allows to subscribe to YT channels without logging in)
- <u>EasyJSON (Easy to use small (11 KB) JSON library</u> for Java)
- <u>EasyXML (Easy to use small (13 KB) XML library</u> for Java)

#### **SKILLS**

#### **PROFICIENT IN**

Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, Swift, PureScript, Android Development, iOS Development

#### **FAMILIAR WITH**

C, C++, C# and 24 other Programming Languages

#### **CAN COMMUNICATE IN**

Telugu, English, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil

## **EDUCATION**

**NOV 2021** 

**SYSTEMS EXPERT, ALGOEXPERT.IO** 

**MAY 2021** 

IOS DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

**FEB 2021** 

ANDROID KOTLIN DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY